搞什么鬼
What the hell?
我的天 他把媽的舊車也拖來了
Oh, my God. He brought Mom's old car?
要知道 那玩意再適合迪迪不過了
You know, that thing was perfect for Dede --
又吵 又偏左
loud, pulled way to the left,
還總在公共場合抽風
and constantly broke down in public.
我前妻迪迪兩個月前去世了
My ex-wife, Dede, died two months ago,
她丈夫杰瑞把她想留給我們的破爛
and her husband, Jerry, drove down with a bunch of junk
都拉了過來
she wanted us to have.
我一直很喜歡杰瑞
I always liked Jerry.
那你為什么總用奇怪的眼神看他
Then why did you always look at him funny?
因為我知道他所面臨的悲慘命運
Because I knew what he was in for.
我看人們登上泰坦尼克號的錄像時
Same way I look at the footage of those people
也是那種眼神
boarding the Titanic.
杰 這是給你的
Jay, this is for you.
老天爺 那是她的灰嗎
Oh, God. Is that her?
不不不 這是你們度蜜月時
No, no, no. Apparently this is a jar of sand
從邁阿密海灘帶回的沙子
from your honeymoon in Miami Beach.
是啊 當時我們住在楓丹白露酒店
Oh, yeah. We stayed at the Fontainebleau.
猜猜我們在電梯里遇到了誰
Guess who we took an elevator with?
杰基·格利森[演員]
Jackie Gleason.
我告訴他我們才在《蜜月期》
I told him we were the honeymooners,
他開玩笑威脅道要把迪迪揍到月亮上去
and, as a joke, he threatened to punch Dede to the moon.
笑點在哪
Why is that funny?
我就是這個意思 哪里好笑
Well, that's my point. It wasn't right.
克萊爾 你媽想把她的舊跑車留給你
Claire, your mom wanted you to have her old sports car.
太好了
Oh, great.
米奇爾 她的珠寶給你
And Mitchell, you get to keep her jewelry.
這么說克萊爾得到了跑車
Oh, so Claire gets a car,
而我得到了一盒子綠松石
and I get a, uh, box of turquoise.
你想交換嗎
Want to trade?
不 這樣挺好的
No. No, it's fine.
我家有個"不到十三歲的少女"
I have a preteen girl at home,
"她"喜歡玩扮裝游戲
and she likes to play dress-up.
再說 莉莉或許也會喜歡
And, you know, Lily might like it, too.
米奇爾 克萊爾 迪迪想讓你倆決定
Mitchell and Claire, Dede wanted you two to decide
誰把她帶回家
who gets to keep her.
抱歉 杰 她沒把你包括在內
Sorry, Jay. She left you out of this one.
別擔心 杰瑞 我有沙子就夠了
No worries, Jerr. I'm good with the sand.
等等 你說"把她帶回家"是什么意思
Hang on. Uh, what do you mean, "Gets to keep her"?
那就是迪迪
That's Dede.
我們把她的骨灰和根垛有機融合在一起了
We had her ashes organically fused with the root ball.
太像老媽的風格了
That is so Mom.
是啊 最后還要留樣東西讓我們爭
I know. Setting up one last thing for us to fight over,
因為我們誰都不想要那棵樹
because neither of us want that tree.
因為我們都想要那棵樹
Because both of us want the tree.
什么
What?
輕松解決
That was easy.
酷
Oh, cool.
看 外婆把她家的舊玩具箱留給我們了
Look. Nana left us her old toy box from her house.
保佑她那顆有囤積癥的心
Aww, bless her hoarding heart.
還記得我過去總躲在這里
Remember how I used to hide in here
像嚇人的怪物一樣跳出來嗎
and pop out like a scary monster?
那時我還有那么多潛能
I had so much promise back then.
能震動的棍馬
A stick horse that vibrates?
我一直搞不懂用意
I never got the point.
我說不好
I don't know,
但我記得過去一"騎"就是好久
but I remember spending hours riding on it.
我也是
Same.
快看這個 艾麗克斯
Oh. Lookie here, Alex.
你最大屈辱的根源
The source of your greatest shame --
我能解開但你解不開的積木拼圖
the puzzle that I solved but you never did.
誰在乎
Who cares?
當時我們都是蠢小孩
We were just dumb kids.
不
Uh, no.
我們才是蠢小孩
We were dumb kids,
而你是小天才
and you were the genius.
那肯定讓你寢食難安吧
That must eat away at you.
拜托
Please.
我是名牌大學的尖子生
I'm top of my class at a prestigious university,
我和別人共同發明了一種
and I co-invented a technology
應用于天體物理學和醫學的技術
that has applications to astrophysics and medicine.
把那該死的積木拼圖給我
And give me that damn puzzle!
我的天 是露露
Oh, my God, it's Lulu!
她曾是我最喜歡的玩具
She was my favorite toy.
我猜我只是很想念外婆
I guess I-I just really miss Nana.
我還懷孕了
Also I'm pregnant.
迪蘭和我還沒告訴任何人
Dylan and I haven't told anyone
因為我還在努力接受這個事實
because I'm still trying to get my head around it,
可抱著露露讓一切變得那么真實
but holding Lulu made it so real.
我就要有一個活生生的寶寶了
I'm gonna have an actual baby.
我壓力好大
Aah, I'm so stressed!
我真希望現在還是五十年代
I wish it was the '50s
那時人們還認為懷孕時喝酒抽煙
when it was still healthy to drink and smoke
不會不健康
when you're pregnant.
我等不及翻新這臺寶貝了
I cannot wait to restore this baby.
高中時欺負我的惡霸就有一臺
My high school bully had one.
你肯定想不到這車能跑多快
You'd be surprised how fast this thing can go.
能輕松追上騎著單車
No problem catching up with a kid on a bike
提前十分鐘離校的孩子
who left school 10 minutes early.
我不確定我希望車庫里
I don't know if I want another
又多一件慢慢生銹的半成品
half-finished project rusting away in the garage.
我放棄機器割草機的唯一原因
The only reason I stopped working on robot lawnmower
是因為它開始變得太聰明了
was 'cause he started getting too smart.
別這樣 親愛的 我們留著吧
Come on, honey. Let's keep it.
它讓我想起我媽能有多瘋狂
It reminds me of how crazy my mom could be.
什么樣的老媽會有這樣的車
I mean, what mother has a car like this?
這樣如何 我們開出去兜一圈
How's this? We take it for one drive.
假如回來時你臉上沒有笑容
If you're not smiling by the time we come back,
我們就不要了
we get rid of it.
-只兜一圈 -只兜一圈
- One drive? - One drive.
- One drive. - One drive.
她過去總把我和米奇爾
Ugh, she used to double-buckle me and Mitchell
一起綁在副駕
into the front seat.
再加上她自制的電熱毯
Between that and the homemade electric blankets,
我倆還活著簡直是奇跡
it's a wonder we're still alive.
怎么請了水管工
What's with the plumber?
喬又把海王玩具沖下馬桶了嗎
Did Joe flush his Aquaman down the toilet again?
不 我那些親戚離開時
No. When my cousins left,
告訴我客房沒有熱水
they said that the hot water in the guest bedroom was not working.
水管工剛才說一切正常
The plumber just said that there's nothing wrong.
是有人把熱水關了
Someone turned it off.
八成是喬
Probably Joe.
我們要怎么罰他
So, what are we thinking?
一周不準約小朋友來家玩
No play dates for a week?
我知道是你關的
I know it was you.
你想讓他們走 就把他們凍走了
You wanted them gone, and you froze them out.
我不承認有做過
I'm admitting nothing,
但你說你的一個親戚會來這里住一天
but you said one cousin would be here for one day,
結果三個人在這里住了一周
and there were three here for a week.
我才沒說過
I never said that.
為什么杰瑞還在這
Why is Jerry still here?
是啊 肯定出什么事了
I know. Something must be wrong.
他像個受傷的小老頭一樣坐在車里
He's sitting in the car like a sad little man.
我們得讓他進來坐坐
We have to go and invite him in.
別 別 別 他總會走的
No, no, no, no. He'll move off eventually.
歌洛... 周四的街道清掃會掃走他的
Glor-- Street sweeping is Thursday.
杰瑞 你還好嗎
Jerry, is everything okay?
你的車需要人幫忙推一把嗎
Yeah, does your truck need a push?
這就是最該死的地方
It's the darnedest thing.
我好像開不走了
I can't seem to drive away.
放下迪迪的東西是要做的最后一件事
Dropping off Dede's stuff was the last check on the ol' list.
我現在很迷茫[迷路]
Heck if I'm now feeling pretty lost.
我懂 你沿這條街往前開
Yeah, I get it. Listen, you just drive down this street,
右轉 就到高速路了
turn right, and you'll hit the freeway.
杰瑞 進來坐坐吧
Jerry, just come inside.
不了 我不用了
No, I couldn't.
對 要愛戴有尊嚴的男人
Yeah, got to love a man with pride.
愛和自豪送你快樂上高速
That's the thing that'll serve you well on the freeway.
進來吧 我給你做點吃的
Just come inside, I'll make you something to eat,
你想待多久就待多久
and you can stay as long as you want.
是吧 杰
Right, Jay?
總有一天 歌洛莉亞
One of these days, Gloria.
總有一天干嘛
One of these days what?
沒什么 我就隨口一說
Nothing. Just one of these days.
好了 我們把媽媽放在哪里好呢
All right. Where should we put Mom?
不能離窗戶太近
Uh, not too close to the window.
不想以后二十年為了不讓她聽到小聲說話
Don't want to spend the next 20 years whispering.
好 這么說 你媽可以是棵樹
Okay, so, your mom can be a tree,
但是我跟你說我的叔叔霍納斯
but when I told you my Uncle Honus
跌進打谷機 結果來年春天
fell into a thresher and the next spring,
一只長得和他一模一樣貓頭鷹帶著他的
an owl appered with his exact face
懷表出現的時候 你嗤之以鼻
and pocket watch, you poo-pooed it.
你為什么非要為難我
Why are you being so difficult?
因為我們最初在一起的時候
Because when we first got together,
你答應我有一天我們會搬回
you promised that someday we would move back
我們家的農場 但是每一年
to my family farm, and every year,
這所謂的終有一天都被拋在腦后
the someday gets kicked further down the road
像愛管閑事的人口普查員被嫌棄一樣
like a nosy census taker.
而且 一旦你把你媽種在這里
And -- And once you plant your mom here,
我們就永遠別想走了
we're never gonna leave.
這么說有點過
That's crazy.
而且我 我覺得你應該不想
And I-I-I don't think you want to talk
跟我扯到我們以前做過的承諾吧
about promises we made back then.
你什么意思
What are you suggesting?
-我說到的都做到了 -真的嗎
- I've kept every promise I've made. - Really?
你答應過在我余生的每個月送我一枝玫瑰
You promised me a rose a month for the rest of my life,
所以我估計這么算我已經死了十五年了
so I guess I dropped dead 15 years ago.
我讀了一篇文章說這樣對環境...
I read an article that said it was environmentally ins--
我就沒見你看過書
I've never seen you read an article.
還有 你說你一定會看《E.T》
Also, you said you'd finally watch "E.T.",
我有史以來的最愛電影
my all-time favorite movie.
那個電影太蠢了
Oh, it just seems so stupid.
有什么好看的
What am I caring about?
一個皺巴巴的木偶
A wrinkly puppet with a Christmas light
嚇人的指尖還長著圣誕彩燈
at the end of his creepy finger?
真要這么比嗎 我說我會看
And really? Me saying I would watch
什么感人熱淚電影和你答應我有一天
some pandering sap-fest is the same
我能和家人重聚能一樣嗎
as you saying I would someday be reunited with my family?
承諾就是承諾
A promise is a promise.
太同意了
I couldn't agree more.
簡直不能更同意
所以 你基本沒錯過多少好戲
So, anyway, you haven't missed much around here.
抱歉給你們添麻煩
I'm sorry to be such a burden.
我不知道怎么從這件事走出來
It's just I don't know how to move on.
我一直在拼命燒香
I've been going through incense like crazy.
可憐人
Oh, poor man.
來 吃點東西
Here. Eat something.
我知道你吃素 所以我做了番茄湯
I know you're a vegetarian, so I made you tomato soup.
看起來很好吃 有沒有給我剩一點
That looks pretty good. You have any left over for me?
我扔了
Aw, I threw it out.
我知道你不喜歡任何東西待太久
I know that you don't like things staying around too long.
她在生我的氣
She's mad at me.
她的親戚待得太久了 我不歡迎他們
Her family overstayed their welcome,
就把熱水停了
and I turned off the hot water,
還把房間里的燈泡卸了幾個
took a few bulbs out of the room.
你懂的 婚后生活
You know how it is when you're married.
迪迪和我從沒拌過嘴
Dede and I never had a cross word.
真的假的
What?
那不可能
That is not possible.
是真的 如果氣氛開始緊張
Yep. If things ever got heated,
我就走到她身后
I'd come up behind her,
把我的手纏繞到她脖子上
put my hands on her neck...
這想法我也有過
I'm with you so far.
然后給她按摩 跟她說她是對的
...then massage her and tell her she was right.
但是如果是她的錯呢
But what if she wasn't right?
那只是自尊心作祟
That's ego talking.
在佛教里 我們相信戰勝自己
In Buddhism, we believe it's better to conquer yourself
要比贏一千場戰役好得多
than win a thousand battles.
怪不得尼泊爾每次奧運都"大獲全勝"
That's why Nepal is always crushing it at the Olympics.
杰 明智的男人會走過去
Jay, an enlightened man would go over there
說" 歌洛莉亞 我愛你并且尊重你"
and say, "Gloria, I love and respect you,
所以毋庸置疑我也愛你的家人且尊重他們
so of course I love and respect your family.
對不起"
I am sorry."
但是都是她的錯
But it was all her fault.
她不愿意承認 但是她跟我說的就是
She wouldn't admit it, but she told me
一個親戚來這待一天
one person was staying with us for one day.
這是她的原話[短信] 但是她言下之意是什么
That's her text, but what was her subtext?
杰瑞 你真是個天才
Jerry, you're a genius.
她給我發過短信
She sent me a text.
我有證據
I have the proof.
歌洛莉亞
Gloria?
-干嘛 -看這里
- What? - Right here.
你不用走過來
You don't have to walk over here.
你字體那么大我從房間那頭都能看見
I can read your giant font from across the room.
"杰 回家之后不要報警
"Jay, don't call the police when you come home.
家里的是我親戚
It's my cousin.
他要跟我們住一天"
He's staying with us for one day."
我看看
Let me see.
再跟我捋一遍那個佛教的胡說八道
Walk me through that Buddhist nonsense again.
有意思吧 享受著耳邊風吹和清新空氣
Fun, huh? Feel that wind and smell that air.
是啊 這車太顛簸了
Yeah, it's so bumpy.
那是運動化懸掛系統 我和路之間毫無阻礙
Sports suspension. Nothing between me and the road
除了我的露關節手套
except my knuckle-less gloves.
你為什么會有這玩意
Why do you even have those?
這是鄧菲家族的怪癖
Oh, a quirk of the Dunphys.
我的手指怕冷 但我的指關節怕熱
My fingers get cold, but my knuckles get hot.
快看啊
Check it out!
有能放八首歌的音響 我超喜歡的
There's an 8-track player. I love it.
我們來聽歌吧
Let's crank something.
沒聽說過這支樂隊 "磁頭清潔帶"
Never heard of this band -- Head Cleaner.
里面有什么我們就聽什么吧
Yeah, why don't we just listen to whatever's in there?
老天啊
Oh, my God.
-這首歌讓我回到了從前 -是啊 我好愛
- Oh, this takes me back. - Yeah, I love it.
* 發動汽車 *
* Get your motor goin' *
* 朝門口馳騁而去 *
* Heading for the doorway *
* 烹煮一場冒險 *
* Cooking an adventure *
* 然后朝門口馳騁而去 *
* And then we make that doorway *
好好玩
So fun!
你笑了 你喜歡這輛車
You're smiling. You love the car.
我剛想起件事
Ah, I just remembered something.
什么事 告訴我
What? Tell me.
是我高中時的事
It's a -- It's a thing from high school.
快說嘛 大路上沒有秘密
Come on. There are no secrets on the open road.
我剛想起我在這輛車上破的處
I just remembered that I lost my virginity in this car.
你說什么來著
What's that now?
我男朋友晚上偷偷把車開出來
Yeah, my boyfriend snuck the car out at night
然后 你懂的
and then, you know...
*他找到了"門口"*
* He found the doorway *
我的指關節熱到不行了
Oh, my knuckles are overheating.
你很在意這件事 是嗎 菲爾
This isn't bothering you, is it, Phil?
你也告訴過我你的第一次啊
I mean, you told me about your first time.
我是為了解釋我為何討厭蜜蜂才說的
I told you about that to explain why I hate bees so much.
我們別再討論這事了
Let's just not talk about this anymore.
好吧
Okay.
* 天生狂野 *
* Born to be wild *
當時播的就是這首歌 對吧
This is the song that was playing, isn't it?
是其中一首
It's one of them.
我去做午飯 你們要吃嗎
I'm gonna fix lunch. Want some?
你居然要吃午飯
You're eating lunch?
是不是有什么我不知道的新網絡挑戰
Is there some new Internet challenge I'm not aware of?
還有 你的娃娃為什么綁了繃帶
And why is your doll in bandages?
你知道我的 我小時候就很愛玩醫生游戲
You know me. I always loved playing doctor.
其實我不小心開車碾過她
The truth is, I accidentally ran her over
把她胳膊扯斷了 本來也沒什么
and ripped her arm off, which might have been fine
但可惜那并不是我今日唯一一次要害死嬰兒
if that was the only baby-mangling issue I had today.
天啊
Oh, my God!
Oh, my God.
我不是當媽的料
I'm not cut out to be a mother.
但話說回頭 真正的嬰兒比娃娃好照顧 對吧
Then again, a real baby is easier than a doll, right?
真正的嬰兒著火了
Like, a real baby would let you know
會讓大人知道
if it was on fire.
老天 你為什么在哭
Oh, God, why are you crying?
你是不是剛贏下最古怪的選美比賽
Did you just win the weirdest beauty pageant ever?
我遵守承諾了 米奇爾 180個月的玫瑰
Promises kept, Mitchell -- 180 months of roses,
以及我剛看了男孩和外星人之間的
and I just watched the most beautiful love story
最美好的愛情故事
between boy and alien.
世人為何就不能擁有孩童般的心呢
Why can't the world have the hearts of children?
我想最令我感動的部分是
You know, I think the thing that touched me the most
我們全力支持ET找到
was how we were really rooting for E.T. to find
回家的路
his way home.
你不小心發現"回家"這個巧合
I bet you were pretty thrilled
一定很激動吧
to stumble upon that coincidence.
我是不討厭啦
I didn't hate it.
總之 我的承諾都兌現了
Anyway, I'm all caught up in the promises department.
輪到你了
Your serve.
小卡 我剛開始到地檢署上班
Cam, I just started at the D.A.'s office.
短期內不能搬家
I -- I can't move anytime soon.
再說 莉莉上學怎么辦
Plus, what about Lily's school?
我老家也有學校啊
They have schools in Grasshopper.
真的有嗎
Do they?
-再說 莉莉在這里有很多朋友 -真的有嗎
- Plus, Lily has so many friends here. - Does she?
你們在講我嗎
Did I hear my name?
你們倆八婆在瞎聊什么呢
What are you two yentas gabbing about?
我們剛在討論
We were just talking about
搬去爺爺奶奶的農場
moving to Grandma and Grandpa's farm
就在龍卷風多發地區的中心
in -- in the heart of Tornado Alley.
天啊 小卡 你看 她都嚇壞了
Oh, God. Cam -- Cam. Look, she's clearly terrified.
好吧 別擔心 親愛的
Yeah, well, don't worry, sweetie,
因為這事已經定下了
because it's already been determined.
我們這輩子都留在這里
We're staying here forever,
因為另一個爸爸要把去世的奶奶種到后院里
because other daddy is planting dead Nana in the backyard.
我不玩了
I'm out.
讓其中一個孩子接收她的骨灰
Okay, it was my mother's last wish
是我媽媽的遺愿 而克萊爾不想要她
that one of us take her, and Claire doesn't want her.
你想讓我怎么做
What do you want me to do?
那你想讓我怎么做
Well, what do you want me to do?
那個農場已經在我家族百年了
The farm has been in my family for 100 years.
下一個繼承人是我 你也知道我爸的
You know, I'm next in line, and you know Daddy.
他身體大不如前了
H-He's slowing down.
你媽剛給我們發了他贏得
Your mother just sent us a video of him
水上踩滾木比賽的視頻
winning a log-rolling contest.
他參加的是老年組 而且第二天他累壞了
Only in his age group, and he was so spent the next day,
公雞第一次打鳴他都沒醒來
he slept through his first rooster crow
叫賴床的打鳴他也沒醒
and his snooze rooster crow.
你就承認吧 你根本沒打算
Just admit it -- you have no intention
遵守承諾 搬去密蘇里州
of keeping your promise of moving to Missouri.
其實 你說得對
You know what? You're right.
我永遠無法想象自己住在那個農場里 抱歉
I -- I can't ever imagine myself living on that farm. I'm sorry.
你說出來了
Well, there it is.
我真慶幸ET不是降落在你家里
I'm just glad E.T. didn't land at your house.
別用那種眼神看我
Okay, don't give me that look.
你以后會回密蘇里州的
You'll get to go back to Missouri
等你媽從監... 公主營回來
when your mom gets released from pris-- uh, princess camp.
你口香糖嚼得很兇嘛 是不是
You're really hitting the gum pretty hard, aren't you?
我該怎么做 就這么壓下去嗎
How do I do this? Do I -- Do I just push down?
我不知道啊
I don't know.
不行
Nope.
我一開始不太順利
I got off to a slow start,
但最終我找到了自己的節奏
but eventually I -- I found my rhythm.
而且 在我弄斷灑水器的管子后
And -- And once I broke that sprinkler line,
漏出來的水基本幫我把坑挖好了
the -- the water did most of the digging for me.
來吧 再拉一下就行了
All right, let's go. Just one last pull.
壓到腳踝了
Ah! Ah, okay, that's my ankle.
我卡住了
I'm stuck.
卡爾 我要你進去...
Cal, so, what I'm gonna need you to do is go insi--
卡爾 卡爾
Cal. Cal!
什么 你說什么 孩子
What? What is it, boy?
米奇爾
Mitchell?
他遇到麻煩了
H-He's in trouble?
困在洞里了 快帶我去
Trapped in a hole? Show me.
-天啊 你在作弊 -我沒有
- Oh, my God, you're cheating. - No.
你明顯在看拼圖攻略啊
You're looking at ways to solve the puzzle.
那不然你怎么拼得出 你這蠢貨
How'd you do it, you pea-brain?
我怎么回事
What is wrong with me?
也許約翰遜博士說得對
Maybe Dr. Johnson is right.
我真的沒有住到火星上的心理素質
Maybe I don't have what it takes to live on Mars.
住手 住手
Stop! Stop.
不是你的錯
It's not you.
我拼完拼圖后
After I solved the puzzle,
我想讓你拼不起來
I wanted to make sure you couldn't,
所以我拆了幾片
so I broke a few pieces,
跟其它的粘在一起
glued some others together.
你不可能拼起來的
It can't be solved.
我都因為這破拼圖做噩夢了
I've had nightmares over that puzzle!
心理治療時還因為這個哭了
I cried about it in therapy!
不 別碰頭發 發型都搞亂了
Stop! Not the hair! You're gonna fizz it.
怎么回事 松手啊
Hey, what the hell? Break it up.
盧克玩黑的
Luke's not playing fair.
是啊 你讓他覺得自己很笨
Yeah, well, you make him feel dumb,
他還表現出毫不在意的樣子
and he acts like it doesn't bother him,
但他真的在意 還有盧克
but it does. And, Luke,
這么耍一個焦慮的人可不像你啊
you know better than to mess with someone so uptight.
我們怎么說的來著
What do we always say?
不許玩壞艾麗克斯 她是我們的人生保障
Don't break Alex. She's our safety net.
現在 你倆都冷靜點
Now, you both need to calm down.
盧克 走開平靜一下
Luke, walk it off.
糟糕
Oh, no.
露露在哪兒
Where's Lulu?
什
Wh--
娃娃嗎
The doll?
誰在乎啊
Who cares?
海莉 你今天怎么回事
Haley, what's going on with you today?
你還好嗎
Are you okay?
好吧
Okay, um...
別人都不知道 特別是老爸老媽
So, no one else knows, especially Mom and Dad,
你不能告訴任何人
so you can't tell anybody, but...
我懷孕了
I'm pregnant.
你懷孕了
You're pregnant?
靠 盧克
Damn it, Luke!
拜托 你們別這樣看我好嗎
Guys, don't look at me like that, okay?
你們肯定覺得我是不負責任的蠢貨吧
You must think I'm some irresponsible idiot, don't you?
這個 有點
Um, uh, it's a -- Wow, that's --
你懷 信息量好大
You got -- That's a lot to process.
我
I...
你知道孩子爸爸是...
D-Do you know who's the --
是迪蘭
It's Dylan's.
這樣很好啊
Oh. What a joyous --
省省吧
Oh, save it.
他其實表現得很好
He's been great, actually.
我才一團糟 你看露露
I'm the disaster. I mean, look at Lulu.
我一定會是個糟糕的母親
I'm gonna be a horrible mother.
首先 這只是個娃娃
Okay, first, it's just a doll.
而且我們從小其實就一直受你照顧啊
And you've been taking care of us our whole lives.
對啊 記不記得以前你總幫我挑
Yeah. Remember how you used to pick out
我的開學日服裝 免得我挨揍
my first day of school outfit so I wouldn't get beat up?
還有我給自己讀睡前故事時
Or how you'd hold the book
你總是幫我撐著書
while I read myself a bedtime story?
你現在還是啊
And you're still doing it.
還有你剛剛跑過來 輕而易舉阻止了我們打架
You just swooped in and handled our fight like a pro.
你這么善解人意 又有愛心 還霸氣四射
And you're understanding and loving and a total badass.
她說得對
She's right.
你總是能夠平息矛盾
You're the kind of person that can patch things up
比如 如果艾麗克斯發現
if, say, Alex ever found out
我修改了她的魔方上的貼紙
that I re-arranged the stickers on her Rubik's Cube.
你這個混...
You son of a --
頭發 頭發 海莉救我
Aah! Hair, hair! Haley, help!
好吧 我都樂開花了
Oh. Well, I'm smiling,
我想這輛車可以留下來了
so I guess we're keeping the car.
不 你知道嗎 你說得對
No, you know what? You're right.
這車不安全 只會占地兒
It's not safe, and it's just gonna take up space.
親愛的 我說錯什么了嗎
Honey, did I say something wrong?
讓你不舒服了
Are you feeling bad?
我想說實話
Well, I-I guess if I'm being honest,
我有點擔心我一坐進這車里頭
I'm a-a little worried that every time I get in the car,
我就會想象你和...
I'll picture you and, uh...
陶德
Todd.
-陶德 -陶德
- Todd? - Todd.
以前霸凌我的人也叫陶德
Todd was the name of my bully.
感覺更真實了
It's getting realer.
要是換作是你
I mean, how would you feel
開一輛我在里面失去第一次的豪車
about driving around in the sweet ride
會是什么感覺
I lost my virginity in?
你覺得你真能找到那輛
Do you really think you can track down
文藝復興主題市集上的牛車嗎
the ox cart from the Renaissance fair?
我在牛車上只進行到二壘
I only got to second base in the ox cart.
如果你覺得不舒服 我們就把車賣掉
If it makes you uncomfortable, we can sell the car.
-真的嗎 -當然
- Really? - Yeah.
謝謝
Thank you.
但無論如何
But for what it's worth,
我不想留這輛車
I don't want to keep it
不是因為我在這里車震爽翻過好多次
because I had so much great sex in it.
-好多次 -不 是因為第二天發生的事
- So much? - No, it's because of what happened the next day.
我老媽
My mom,
她在車座底下發現了避孕套包裝袋
ugh, she found the condom wrapper under the seat,
她一定嚇壞了
and it must have freaked her out.
但是她沒有羞辱我
But instead of shaming me
或者給我好好上一課 讓我丟臉
or -- or embarrassing me with some long, awful lecture,
她非常酷
she was cool.
她只想確認我一切都好
She wanted to make sure that I was okay with everything
還有那經歷也是美好的
and that it had all been a good experience.
但是
But...
這一定是她想讓我留著這輛車的原因
That must be why she wanted me to have the car.
那段對話對她和我都很有意義
That talk meant as much to my mom as it did to me.
她好貼心啊
That's incredibly sweet,
如果這車真的對你那么重要 你應該留下來
and, if it means that much to you, you should keep it.
但我不知道自己會不會舒服
But I doubt I'll ever feel comfortable in it.
這個好辦
We can fix that.
看樣子好像不錯哦
I like where this is going.
我要給你我在這里體驗過的最棒的車震
I'm gonna make you the best sex I ever had in this car.
這樣壓力太大了 目標前三就好
That's a lot of pressure. Let's aim for top three.
歌洛莉亞 我有話要說
Gloria. I have something to say.
我的辦法浪費了我一部手機 水管工也來了兩次
My approach cost me a phone and a second visit from the plumber,
所以我決定嘗試杰瑞的建議
so I decided to try Jerry's advice
向歌洛莉亞由衷真誠地道歉
and give Gloria a heartfelt, sincere apology.
假裝誰不會啊
How hard could that be to fake?
我不該趕走你的親戚
I was wrong to chase off your cousins.
對不起 我沒有...
I'm sorry that I didn't...
也考慮到你的心情
take your feelings into consideration.
你應該受到尊重
You deserve to be respected.
我當時應該說的是我愛你
What I should've said was I love you,
所以我也愛你的家庭
so I love your family.
請原諒我的無禮之舉
Please forgive me for my rude behavior.
杰 我一直就只想要這個而已
Jay, this is all I ever wanted.
由你主動來對我這樣
For you to come to me like this,
對我真的意義非凡
it means the world to me.
我也很對不起
I'm sorry.
我當時也應該更坦白我親戚要來的事情
I should've been more forward about my cousin's visit.
也很對不起砸了你的手機
And I was wrong for crushing your cellphone.
你能原諒我嗎
Can you ever forgive me?
或許需要點時間 但這還用說嗎
Well, it may take a little while, but sure,
我當然會原諒你
I guess I can.
你知道我接下來要怎么做嗎
You know what I'm going to do?
我要去你喜歡的那家肉店
I'm gonna go to that butcher shop that you like.
然后如果杰瑞不介意的話
And, if Jerry doesn't mind,
我也要給你買一塊上好牛排當晚飯
I'm gonna buy you a beautiful steak for dinner.
你的家 你怎么方便怎么來
Hey, it's your house. You do what's best for you.
如果來我家 我能穿多少穿多少
Come to my house, I'm going to be nude.
我們永遠都不會去你家 杰瑞
We're never going to go to your house, Jerry.
你聽到了嗎 斯黛拉
Did you hear that, Stella?
我們有牛排吃啦
We're gonna have a steak.
杰瑞 你真是個天才
Jerry, you're a genius.
-簡直改變人生啊 -我怎么跟你說的
- This is life-changing. - What did I tell you?
真希望我當年就開始這么做
I wish I had tried this years ago.
這樣我當年跟迪迪的生活就能勉強熬過去了
This would've made my life with Dede downright tolerable.
誰知道呢
Who knows?
說不定我們還能有快樂人生
Maybe we even could've been happy.
很慶幸你能這么想
I'm glad you think so.
但這話跟我說不合適吧
But I'm not the one you need to tell.
迪迪 是我 杰 就想跟你問聲好
Hey, Dede, it's me, Jay. Just wondering how you're doing.
爸
Dad?
我們這里是周六
Uh, it's Saturday here.
你又不是在語音留言
You're not leaving a voicemail.
用心交流
From the heart.
我想跟你說的是
What I wanted to say is
在我們的感情中 我有很多事可以做得更好
I could've handled a lot of things better in our relationship.
我想我當年不是什么好伴侶
I guess I wasn't a very good partner.
常常惹你
I dug in a lot.
也從沒站在你的角度想事情
I never thought of things from your point of view.
可能我總是只想到滿足自己
I guess I always needed to get my own way.
總之 你是個好女人
Anyway, you were a good woman,
我們也有過一些歡樂時光
and we had some fun times,
尤其是床上
especially in the sack.
"床事"從未有過問題
Never had a problem there.
謹言慎行 你是在跟我的老婆說話
Careful. That's my wife you're talking to.
抱歉 杰瑞 好啦
Oh, sorry, Jerr, yeah. Okay.
我希望你能夠成長為一棵健壯大樹
I hope you grow up into a nice, big tree,
也希望你不會染上蟲害
a-and I hope you don't get any of those beetles
會弄死植物的那種
that are killing everything.
等以后你在這落地生根了
And when you settle in in a little while,
或許我會帶喬來爬你
maybe I'll bring Joe over and he can climb you.
阿門
Mm. Amen.
你說完了嗎
You done?
應該吧
Yeah, I think so.
不介意我說兩句吧
Mind if I say a word?
把她交給你了
She's all yours.
杰是個大氣男人
Jay was a big man.
他跟他的老婆道歉了
He apologized to his wife.
你知道她怎么做了嗎
And do you know what she did?
她也道歉回去了
She apologized back!
你有跟我道歉過一次嗎
Did you ever do that even once?!
我跟你道歉過上千次吧
I apologized to you a thousand times,
而你只讓我自己憋著火
and you let me just eat it.
我受夠跟你說你永遠都是對的了
Well, I'm tired of telling you you're always right,
因為你猜怎么著
'cause guess what?
那只海豚壓根就認不得你
That dolphin did not recognize you.
你的俳句有太多音節了
Your haikus had too many syllables.
還有相信我 素食者也需要用止汗除臭劑
And trust me, vegans do need deodorant!
好啦 走吧
All right. Come on.
來吧 小家伙 讓哥請你吃上好牛排
Come on, kid. Let me buy you a nice steak.
好
Yeah.
來 給
Hey. Here.
我想你吃點東西
I-I want you to eat something.
小心
Be careful.
謝謝你對我這么無微不至
Thank you for taking such good care of me,
哪怕你心里不高興
even when you're mad.
沒 天啊 我沒有不高興
No. My gosh, I am not mad.
我也不該逼你的
And I shouldn't have pushed.
對不起 但如果我們今天學到一件事
I-I'm sorry, but, you know, if we learn one thing today,
那就是你不可能在農村里活下來
it's that you couldn't survive on a farm.
我會沒事的
I'll be fine,
-因為我會有你的陪伴 -什么
- because I'll be with you. - What?
我想... 當我用你的角度看這事
I guess w-when I look at things from your point of view,
我的確做出了承諾
I -- I made a promise.
如果你爸爸真的需要你接手一切
When your dad needs you to take over the farm,
我愿意加入
I'm in.
米奇爾 你這話對我意義重大
Mitchell, that means so much to me,
你也會喜歡那一切的
and you're gonna love it.
清新空氣 也沒有惱人車潮
The fresh air, and there's no traffic.
等鎮上有你這第二個律師
Oh, and with a second lawyer in town,
我們就能重開法院了
we could reopen the courthouse.
你給羊擠過奶嗎
H-Have you ever milked a goat?
你有試過從牛奶罐直接喝剛擠的牛奶嗎
Have you ever had fresh milk right from the spigot?
好喝到不行
Oh, unbelievable.
但你也得小心蛇蟲鼠蟻
You do have to be careful of snakes and mice and rats.
那里有巨多田鼠
There's a ton of field mice.
我很怕 小時候有一只沿著我的袖子爬上來了
They scare me. One ran up my sleeve one time when I was a kid.
這車比我印象中小 可能我沒那么靈活了
This car is smaller than I remember. I think I'm just less flexible?
我大腿好像抽筋了
I think I threw out my lap.
我們剛才... 只是在清理車庫
We were um... just cleaning out the garage.
少來 我們全聽到了
Nice try, we heard everything.
不過在快"結束"的時候
Although around the finish line,
我們有點不確定哪個聲音是誰了
we kind of lose track of who's who.
真不敢相信媽又抓到你在車上做愛
I can't believe Mom caught you having sex in the car again.
你叫那棵樹媽嗎
You are calling the tree Mom?
行吧
Okay.
聽我說 在經過一番討論后
So listen, after some reflextion,
我們覺得她在你這里會比較好
we decided that she might be be off here.
在你拒絕之前...
Before you say no.
我也想要這樣
I would actually like that.
車庫里的叫聲是怎么回事
Hey! What was those screeching in the garage?
浣熊又回來了嘛
Are the raccoons back?
靠
Damn it!